（政(せい)）この戦 勝利のために
王騎(おうき)を討とうというのではない
The point of this war is not obtaining victory by killing Wang Qi.
そもそも 王騎の首こそが狙い
Their primary goal is Wang Qi's head.
そのための戦なのだ
（昌文君(しょうぶんくん)）しかし…
That is why they are fighting.
But...
死ぬな 王騎よ
（昌文君）大王…
Don't die, Wang Qi.
My king...
私は多くの戦場で
王騎と くつわを並べてきました
I have fought alongside Wang Qi in many battlefields.
王騎の強さは底が知れない
His strength knows no end.
Wang Qi, the Mystery Bird of Qin,
そんな王騎が… 秦国(しんこく)の怪鳥が―
こんなことで
倒れたりしないはずです
will not be defeated by a something such as this.
（政）
俺も そう思っている　だが もし…
I think so as well.
But if...
（昌文君）“もし”？
If?
（政）もし…
If...
the man known as Li Mu is an even more remarkable man than Wang Qi,
李牧(りぼく)という男が王騎以上の傑物なら
事態は変わる
then the circumstances will be different...
（昌文君）まさか そんなことは…
Unthinkable... Such a thing could not...
だから 仮定の話だ
俺は 王騎の力を信じる
That's why it's just a supposition.
I believe in Wang Qi's strength.
しかし 信(しん)… もしものときには
王騎を守ってくれ
But Xin... if something does happen, protect Wang Qi...
I still need Wang Qi.
俺には まだ 王騎が必要なのだ
頼む 信！
I'm counting on you... Xin...
（信）アア… 新手の敵だ
It's a new enemy...
（渕(えん)）信どの こ… これは 一体…
Lord Xin, what in the world is this...?
（信）ワナだ！
It's a trap...!
It seems the enemy moved faster than I predicted.
（王騎）私の予測より
敵の動きは早かったようですねえ
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）王騎の考えでは―
Wang Qi's prediction was that it would take another half a day before the Li Mu Army would arrive.
李牧軍が到着するまで
あと半日は かかるはずであった
実際 李牧軍は―
And in fact, the Li Mu Army was indeed hidden in the place that Wang Qi had predicted.
王騎の予測した場所に
潜ませてあった
では なぜ李牧軍は それより
はるかに早く到着したのか？
So why was it that the Li Mu Army arrived so much sooner?
その理由は―
It was because of the characteristic of the State of Zhao's mounted soldiers that Li Mu led.
李牧が率いてきた趙国(ちょうこく)の騎馬の
素質にある
古くから
国境に面した北の山岳地帯で―
For them, whom had been positioned at the state's ancient and mountainous northern border, and fought equestrian tribes like the Xiongnu,
騎馬民族 匈奴(きょうど)と
戦ってきた彼らにとって―
mountain valleys and such were no obstacle whatsoever.
山あいなど障害ではなかったのだ
そのため 李牧軍は
山々を迂回(うかい)することなく―
Because of that, the Li Mu Army did not have to take a detour around the mountains,
まっすぐ決戦の地に
はせることが可能だった
and were able to hurry directly to the area of the decisive battle.
つまり 李牧軍の足は―
In other words, the Li Mu Army's speed
通常の騎馬軍の常識を
大きく上回っていたのである
far surpassed that of what was generally known for usual mounted armies.
そして 李牧は
自軍の行軍の早さを―
And Li Mu even judged that Wang Qi would misread the speed of his army's march.
王騎が読み違えることまで
察していた
王騎が これまで一度も―
This is because he had investigated that Wang Qi had never once personally fought with the armies of the northern region of Zhao.
趙国の北部軍と戦った経歴が
ないことを調べていたからだ
And with Wang Qi having mainly only fought in the central region, he had of course never fought the Xiongnu either.
主に中央を戦場にしていた王騎は
無論 匈奴とも戦っていない
趙国の北部軍にしろ
匈奴にしろ―
Wang Qi, whom had never witnessed the leg power of the northern mounted units,
北の騎馬の足を
目の当たりにしていない王騎には
whether it be the northern state of Zhao's or the Xiongnu's,
その力を推し量ることは
できなかった
was not able to surmise that power.
そのことに気づいた王騎は
初めて小さく汗をかいた
When Wang Qi realized that fact, he let out a small bead of sweat for the first time.
Meanwhile, unable to swallow what was going on around them,
一方
事態の のみ込めぬ王騎軍は―
the Wang Qi Army merely watched in astonishment.
ただただ
がく然とするしかなかった
（李牧軍参謀１）大天旗(だいてんき)を掲げよ！
Raise the Great Deva Flag!
（王騎）私にワナを仕掛けたのは
にわか三大天(さんだいてん)のひとりでしたか
So the one that sprung this trap on me was one of the Three Great Devas?
新たな敵は およそ４万
我が軍 残り6,000
There are about 40,000 new enemies
and my army has 6,000 remaining.
大きく打って出ましたねえ 敵は
The enemy has sallied out quite a large challenge.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）時は紀元前 春秋戦国時代
The setting is before the common era, in the Spring and Autumn Warring States Period.
名もなき存在から
百人隊の将にまでなった少年 信は
Xin, the boy that came from obscurity to become the general of a Hundred-Man Unit,
is now at the center of a historic battle.
今 歴史的な戦いの中心にいた
秦国総大将 王騎と
趙国総大将 龐煖(ほうけん)の一騎打ち
A one-on-one battle between the State of Qin Supreme Commander, Wang Qi,
and the State of Zhao Supreme Commander, Pang Nuan.
因縁深き その戦いに
国家の命運が握られていた
Gripped in that deeply personal battle
is the fate of a kingdom.
Presented by Anime-Destiny
itsumo yori hayaku kietetta hoshi zora ni
いつもより早く消えてった星空に
In a starry sky that disappeared faster than it ever has
Translation
kewl0210
kusanariatta deai wa
重なり合った出会いは
the many piled up meetings we've had
Editing
jagman1x3
ore wo nomikonde iku
俺を呑み込んでいく
swallow me.
kono yume wa kudakenai
この夢は砕けない
This dream cannot be broken.
Timing
rtrs
sabitsukaseta kyoufushin
錆びつかせた恐怖心
Among this rusted fear in my heart
yuragu fuan no naka de
揺らぐ不安の中で
and the anxiety that makes me waver
Typesetting
kewl0210
ame wo saegiru shinjitsu
雨を遮る信実
is a truth that interrupts the rain.
dare ni mo ubaeyashinai
誰にも奪えやしない
No one can take it away,
Karaoke
kewl0210
FZeroWing
onaji keshiki ni hisonda puraido
同じ景色にひそんだプライド
our pride that lurks in the same landscape.
Encode
max80
itsuka kitto kanau ima mo mieru kibou fortitude
いつかきっと叶う 今も見える希望 fortitude
The fortuitous desire I have will definitely come true one day.
yowasa wo sute wa shinai
弱さを捨てはしない
We won't throw away our weaknesses,
oretachi no kienai shiin
俺達の消えないシーン
those are scenes that won't disappear.
furenzokusen no youni hashiru kibou unbreakable heart
不連続線の様に走る希望 unbreakable heart
My desire in my unbreakable heart runs like a discontinuous line.
I knew at the start that there's no end.
QC
Mistral[sA]
I've made up my mind, right now it's the time to take the first step.
Distro
kokus
Kittie
prefix-
Now's the only time.
～♪
I am at the Verge of Death
They are allies, yes?
（カイシン）
味方だろうが… だ… 誰の軍だ？
Wh-Whose army is that?
（趙荘(ちょうそう)軍参謀２）
あんな軍は見たことがない
I've never seen an army like that before.
（趙荘）
よくぞ… よくぞ間に合ってくれた
Good...
Good job making it here in time.
（渕）
こ… これはマズイですよ 信どの
Th-This is bad, Lord Xin.
As things stand, our army is going to lose!
このままでは 我が軍の負けです
（信）言うな 渕さん！
Don't say that, Mr. Yuan!
クッ…
しっかし どうすんだよ？ 王騎将軍
But... What're you gonna do, General Wang Qi?
（カイネ）やりすぎですよ
たかが敵の将軍１人に
This is overkill.
All for just one enemy general...
匈奴相手にも―
We didn't even do something this elaborate against the Xiongnu.
ここまで手の込んだことは
されなかったのに
（魏加(ぎか)）
ハハハッ… たかが敵の将軍１人か
"It's just one general", eh?
若いカイネは 王騎を知らぬな
A young one like you, Kaine, doesn't know Wang Qi I suppose...
ヤツの首は
50の城を取るより価値があるぞ
Capturing his head is worth more than 50 castles.
50？
50?!
（李牧）
魏加どのの言われるとおりです
It is just as Lord Wei Jia says.
国を代表する大将軍の
首というものは―
The head of a Great General that represents a kingdom
その国の軍事の象徴ですからね
is a symbol of that kingdom's military affairs.
そして それを失えば
秦国の武威は失落し
If they lose that, the State of Qin's military power will decrease.
And conversely, the State of Zhao's military power will become a threat to all of the states.
逆に 趙国の武威は
列国の脅威となります
この乱世
弱き所には 人は集まりません
In this turbulent age, people do not gather in weak areas.
Losing military might means that talented people will keep away from them.
武威の失落は才人を遠ざけ―
ひいては
国の弱体化にまで つながる
Retreating is connected to weakening a country.
たかが将軍のひとりといえど―
Even if it's just one general,
the effects that head will bring about are immeasurable.
その首のもたらす影響は
計り知れないのです
Especially if it's Wang Qi's head...
特に王騎の首とあらば…
（李牧軍参謀２）
李牧軍第１陣 突撃！
Li Mu Army, first formation, charge!
D-Don't be daunted! Take your positions!
（王騎軍兵２）
ひ… ひるむな！ 構え！
（王騎軍兵たち）ウワッ！
（尾平(びへい)）お… 王騎将軍の兵が
やられていく…
G-General Wang Qi's soldiers are being beaten...
（松左(しょうさ)）マジかよ…
（竜川(りゅうせん)）これって もう…
Is this... for real...?
It's practically already...
A one-sided massacre.
（澤圭(たくけい)）一方的な虐殺です
王騎将軍…
General Wang Qi...
（王騎軍兵１）殿をお守りしろ！
Protect Lord!
Lord...
（王騎軍兵２）殿… 殿…
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）敵の策略に はまり
敗北が目の前にあることは―
Even the foot soldiers, like Xin's group sensed,
that they had fallen for the enemy's strategy and defeat before their eyes.
歩兵の信たちでさえ感じていた
For Wang Qi that could read further ahead, it was all the more so...
先の読める王騎ならば
なおさらである
（王騎）ンフッ…
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）しかし…
But...
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）王騎は笑った
Wang Qi laughed!
お見事です
Well done. I don't know who you are, but you've completely outdone me.
誰かは知りませんが
完全に してやられましたよ
フゥ… これほどの死地に
落とし込まれたのは―
I think it's been about 20 years since I was thrown into this deadly a situation.
20年ぶりくらいですか
ココココッ…
久しぶりですよ この感じ
It's been so long since I've felt this feeling.
For the first time in so very long
本当に久しぶりに…
血が沸き立ちます
my blood is seething.
While retreating, search for an opening in the enemy to tear apart.
さがりながら
敵のほころびを探りますよ
玄維(げんい) 周央(しゅうおう) しんがりを！
（玄維･周央）はっ！
Xuan Wei, Zhou Yang, take the rear!
Yes, sir!
胡丸(こがん)兄弟は 趙荘軍左翼の裏に―
Hu Wan Brothers, create a base point behind the left wing of the Zhao Zhuang Army.
拠点を作りなさい
（胡丸兄弟）はっ！
Yes, sir!
L-Lord Xin!
し… 信どの！
（信）ああ… 諦めてねえ
Yeah, he's not giving up.
将軍は まだ諦めてねえぞ！
俺らも行くぞ！
Our general still hasn't given up!
Let's go, too!
（王騎軍兵たち）ウワッ！
（羌瘣(きょうかい)）龐煖！
（龐煖）どこへ行く？ 王騎
Pang Nuan!
Where are you going, Wang Qi?
We have yet to reach a conclusion.
決着は まだ ついておらぬぞ！
アア… な… 何だ？ この威圧感
Wh-What is this intimidating air?
こんな すげえの感じたことがねえ
I've never felt something this incredible!
確かに龐煖の武は すげえ
Pang Nuan's military might is definitely strong,
だが 今の将軍は
その はるか上をいっている
but as Wang Qi is now, he is going far above that!
こ… これが秦国の怪鳥なんだ！
Th-This is the Mystery Bird of Qin...?
Wang Qi, now!
王騎 いざ！
（王騎軍兵Ａ）殿をお守りしろ！
Protect Lord!
（王騎軍兵Ｂ）
龐煖を殿から引き離せ！
Separate Pang Nuan from Lord!
（趙荘軍兵１）
龐煖さまをお守りしろ！
Protect Lord Pang Nuan!
（趙荘軍兵２）王騎を殺せ！
Kill Wang Qi!
（羌瘣）
もはや 一騎打ちどころではないな
It's no longer anything like a one-on-one fight.
だが この戦…
But until one falls, this war won't end!
どちらかが倒れるまでは
終わらないぞ
分かってる！ だが 今は…
I know that! But now...
どっちかが死ぬまで
終わらねえ戦であるにしろ…
If it's a war that won't end until one or the other dies...
将軍を殺させるわけには
いかねえんだ！
I won't let you kill my general!
（李牧軍隊長１）
気をつけろ！ 変なガキがいるぞ
Be careful! There's a weird brat there.
First get hi-
まずは そい…
（斬る音）
In this situation where every moment is vital,
（王騎）
一刻を争う この状況で―
I've never had an obstacle as great as this...
これほど重たい障害は
ありませんねえ
やはり あなたには ここで
死んでもらうしかありません！
It seems that I really will need for you to die here!
What's wrong? Your sword strokes are getting disordered.
どうした？ 剣筋が乱れているぞ
しぶとい…
So stubborn...
ウワッ！
（王騎）のみ込まれましたか…
So we've been swallowed?
So the Mystery Bird finally falls to earth...?
（魏加）
ついに“怪鳥 地に落つ”か
フフフッ… この魏加 喜びのあまり
鳥肌が立っておりまする
I, Wei Jia, am so overjoyed that I'm getting goose bumps.
うん？ そのわりには
You don't look that happy.
うれしそうに
見えませんが…
あそこまでの大人物の
死となると
The death of such a great man does not evoke just a simple emotion.
単純な感情だけでは
ないのだ
今 この中華に存在する武将の中で
Right now, among all of the military generals across China,
there is no general hated by more people than Wang Qi.
王騎ほど多くの人間に
憎悪される将軍は いない
Nor is there any general whose death is desired more than that of Wang Qi's.
そして 王騎ほど
その死を望まれている将軍もな
Long ago, that man continuously crushed all of this enemies on every single battlefield.
かつて あの男は
ありとあらゆる戦場において―
敵を撃破し続けた
飛来するがごとく どこにでも現れ
With the way he would appear anywhere, as if he'd flown there and wreak havoc,
その猛威を振るう王騎は
いつしか“秦国の怪鳥”と呼ばれた
he at some point became called the "Mystery Bird of Qin".
The death of such a person
そんなヤツの死は―
秦国と敵対する列国
全ての者の願望であり 夢だ
is the desire... no, the dream of all people across the states that are antagonistic towards Qin!
しかし それは同時に―
But at the same time,
that is also proof recognized by all that Wang Qi is a hero whose name will go down in China's history.
王騎が 中華の歴史に
名を刻む英雄であることを
皆が認めている証しでもある
And that Wang Qi falls today.
だが その王騎が今日 倒れる
伝説の秦国六大将軍
The legendary member of the State of Qin's Six Great Generals, as well as the one rumored to be the strongest of them all, Wang Qi...
その 最強とも
ウワサされた あの王騎が…
なぜか分かるか？ カイネ
And do you know why that is, Kaine?
That is because...
それは…
それは ここにいる李牧さまが―
That is because the man right here, Lord Li Mu, is a monster that even surpasses Wang Qi!
あの王騎を超えるバケモノだからだ
この戦乱の世には 常に傑物が現れ
In this war-torn world, great men always appear.
彼らが その時代を作り上げていく
They create those ages.
Bai Qi, Wang Qi, and the others of the State of Qin's Six Generals,
白起(はくき) 王騎ら秦国の六将に
廉頗(れんぱ)将軍らの趙国三大天
the Lian Po Generals, and the State of Zhao's Three Great Devas.
And now, a formerly great man will disappear,
そして今―
かつての傑物が消え
新たな時代が
幕を開けようとしているのだ
and the curtain on a new age will rise.
無名の者たちの力によってな
By the power of nameless people...
One cannot keep their heart from trembling at such a place as this.
この場にいられることに
心震えずには いられぬわ
では 御免
Now then, excuse me.
ハッ… どこへ行かれる？
Where are you going?
全土が注目する大舞台に―
On this grand stage that the whole nation has their eyes on,
I, Wei Jia, want to leave my mark if even only a little.
僅かでも
この魏加の爪痕を残したく…
Even if it is for doing a dirty job.
たとえ 汚れ役としても…
龐煖さまは 曲がりなりにも三大天
No matter how it happened, Lord Pang Nuan is one of the Three Great Devas.
As we're going into a new age, I cannot allow him to lose his life here.
新時代に向けて ここで命を―
落としていただくわけにも
いきませぬ
（李牧）かたじけない
I greatly appreciate it.
（李牧軍兵１）王騎！
Wang Qi!
我 正に死線にあり
I am truly at the verge of death.
Don't give up to the very end!
最後まで諦めんじゃねえぞ！
分かってんな？
Got that?!
信！
（信）うん？
Xin.
A strange group is coming.
妙な連中が来るぞ
（信）ハッ…
（魏加護衛兵１）円陣を崩さず進め
（魏加護衛兵２）間を開け過ぎるな
Keep moving forward without breaking the circle!
Don't leave too big of a gap!
I will now perform a great deed.
これより大事をなす
１兵たりとも わしに近づけるな
（魏加護衛兵１）ははっ！
Do not let a single soldier get close to me.
Yes, sir!
（信）
王騎将軍のほうに向かっていく
He's heading toward General Wang Qi.
あいつら 将軍を狙っているのか？
（羌瘣）恐らく
Is he going to go after the general?!
Most likely.
Like hell I'll let him.
そうはさせるか！ 馬だ 羌瘣！
A horse! Qiang Lei!
Feixin Unit, charge straight through!
飛信隊は そのまま突き進め！
（兵士たち）オーッ！
（趙荘）
ついに… ついに この時が来たか
Finally... This moment has finally come...
That living legend, Six General Wang Qi will sink to the earth.
あの 生きる伝説の六将 王騎が
地に沈む
中華全土を
震え上がらせ続けた あの王騎が！
That man, Wang Qi, that made all of China tremble!
フフフッ… この私が
大将代理を務めた戦いで王騎が死ぬ
In the battle where I fought as substitute Great General, Wang Qi will die.
フフフッ… 笑わずには おられぬわ
I cannot help but laugh!
My only regret...
唯一の心残りは…
この目で
ヤツの最期を見届けられぬことか
is that it would seem I will not be able to see his end with my own eyes.
I'll be going ahead and waiting for you, Wang Qi!
先に逝(い)って待っているぞ 王騎！
ヌオーッ！
What?!
（王騎軍兵３）なに？
（王騎軍兵４）龐煖に力が！
Pang Nuan's power!
意識が飛んで
枷(かせ)が解けてきましたか
He lost consciousness for moment and the fetters have been broken, have they?
As one who seeks military might, his entire self was captured by revenge.
（李牧）武の求道者(ぐどうしゃ)が 復讐(ふくしゅう)に
我が身をとらわれていたのです
Now that that has disappeared, Pang Nuan has returned to being a pure manifestation of military might.
それが消えた今 龐煖は
純粋な武の化身に戻りましたよ
Lord!
殿！
（王騎）ンフフフッ… まったく…
Honestly.
手ごわい策士と武人を
同時に相手にするのは―
Opposing both a powerful strategist and warrior at once
骨が折れますねえ
is really quite a chore.
こと 策士に対しては いろいろと
考えを巡らせていましたが
I have been thinking about various things in opposition to the strategist,
but there does not seem to be even one plan that I can enact now.
ここから打てる策は…
もはや１つもなさそうです
（李牧軍兵１）諦めよった
あの王騎が諦めよったぞ！
He's given up!
Wang Qi has just given up!
（李牧軍兵２）ハハハッ！
ならば我らが その首もらい受ける
Then we'll be taking possession of that head!
（王騎）ンフフフッ…
誰も“諦めた”とは言ってませんよ
No one said anything about giving up.
策がなければ 力業です
If I have no plan, it'll be a matter of strength.
（王騎）この声を聞く王騎軍の
兵士に言い渡します！
I am announcing this to all soldiers of the Wang Qi Army that can hear!
敵の数は およそ10倍
ならば １人10殺を義務づけます
The enemy's number is approximately 10 times ours!
So I am obligating 10 kills per man!
I will not forgive you for falling before killing 10 men!
敵10人を討つまで
倒れることは許しません
皆 ただの獣と化して戦いなさい！
Everyone, please become mere beasts and fight!
Understand?!
いいですか？
ここからが王騎軍の真骨頂です
Now the Wang Qi Army will show its true worth!
With strength, we will wrench open a means of escape from being on the verge of death!
この死地に
力ずくで活路をこじあけます！
And I, Wang Qi, will always be at your back!
皆の背には
常に この王騎がついていますよ！
どけ！
Out of the way!
あと少しだ… あと少し！
Just a little...
Just a little further!
（王騎軍兵３）あの男を止めろ！
そやつは中華十弓のひとり 魏加だ
Stop that man!
He is one of China's Ten Bows, Wei Jia!
死なせるかよ 王騎将軍！
I won't let you die, General Wang Qi!
（魏加護衛兵１）
ガキが入ってくるぞ！
There's a kid coming in!
（斬る音）
政には あんたが必要なんだ！
Zheng needs you!
Kill him! Don't let him get close to Lord Wei Jia!
（魏加護衛兵２）
殺せ！ 魏加さまに寄せつけるな
第一 俺も あんたとの約束を
果たしてもらってねえ
And most of all, I haven't gotten what I promised with you!
（王騎）さすがです 龐煖
Just as I expected of you, Pang Nuan.
But with that exhausted body...
しかし その消耗した体では…
you cannot defeat me.
（王騎）私は倒せませんよ
Pang Nuan, now the curtain falls!
龐煖 幕です！
（王騎軍兵４）アア…
Lord!
殿ーっ！
命を奪いしは龐煖さまの一刀なれど
His life was taken by Lord Pang Nuan's strike,
それをさせたのは
紛れもなく この魏加の一矢
but what allowed it was none other than the arrow of I, Wei Jia.
この魏加の！
I, Wei Jia!
全中華の人間が非難しても―
Even if you are deprecated by people all across China, none can call you a coward, Wang Qi.
よもや 貴様は
卑怯(ひきょう)とは言うまいな 王騎
（斬る音）
（信）ざけんな てめえ！
Fuck you, bastard!
A damper has been put on our fight.
（龐煖）水を差された…
だから
戦などは つまらんというのだ
That is why things such as war are uninteresting.
だが これは お前の土俵だ
文句は言わせぬ
But this is your arena.
I will hear no complaints.
お前の負けだ 王騎！
This is your defeat, Wang Qi.
（李牧軍兵２）
ハハハッ… 武器を捨ておったぞ
They threw down their weapons.
さあ 終わりだ！ 秦兵を皆殺しに…
Now it's over.
Let's slaughter all of the Qin sol-
Wait!
（王騎）お待ちなさい！
I am quite vexed you would allow defeat to be pushed upon you.
（王騎）勝手に負けを
押しつけられるのは心外ですねえ
我が配下たちにも怒りを覚えます
武器を落とすとは何事ですか？
Even my subordinates must know of anger...
What are you doing dropping your weapons?
たとえ 何が起ころうと―
No matter what happens,
死んでも諦めぬことが
王騎軍の誇りだったはずですよ
it has always been the Wang Qi Army's pride to never to give up, even in death.
（王騎軍兵たち）殿！
Lord!
王騎将軍！
General Wang Qi...
Th-That's unsightly!
（李牧軍兵３）み… 見苦しいぞ
It is already obvious that all of you will die!
（李牧軍兵３）もはや
貴様ら全員の死は明白だろうが！
この死に損ないが！
You death-dodging bastard!
（李牧軍兵３）ウッ…
I have long placed myself on battlefields,
長く戦場に身を置き
and piled up many intense struggles for my life.
苛烈な命のやり取りを
重ねてきました
Perhaps for that reason, I somehow know
そのせいか
不思議と分かるんですよ
ここは まだ死地ではありません
that this is still not the place of my death.
（王騎）信じられないようですねえ
It seems you don't believe me...
Then allow me to prove it to you.
では 証明してあげましょう
まず龐煖を斬り伏せて…
First, I will cut down Pang Nuan.
ウウッ… 何のマネだ？
What is this?
（王騎）将軍とは…
A full general is...
百人将や千人将などと同じく
like a Hundred-Man General or a Thousand-Man General.
They are only different names for positions and ranks.
役職 階級の名称にすぎません
But there are only a handful of humans that can reach that level.
しかし…
そこに たどりつける人間は
ほんのひと握り
It is a place that only those, that can overcome many points of death and render numerous achievements, can reach.
あまたの死地を越え
あまたの功を上げた者だけが
達せられる場所です
As a result, gaining the title of full general
結果 将軍が手にするのは―
is the immense honor of being responsible for and controlling thousands and tens of thousands of lives.
千 万の人間の命を束ね戦う責任と
絶大な栄誉
Therefore, that existence is heavy!
故に その存在は重く
故に まばゆいほどに光り輝く
Therefore, it shines with a dazzling light!
Madness...
バカな… 何なのだ？ 貴様
What are you...?
き… 貴様は 一体 何者だ！
W-What in the world are you?!
（王騎）
ンフフフッ… 決まってるでしょう
Isn't it obvious?
天下の大将軍ですよ！
The greatest general under the heavens!
赤き　血潮
akaki chishio
Crimson blood flowing...
この鼓動は　野望なのか
kono kodou wa yabou na no ka
Is this racing pulse ambition?
幼き日　誓った
osanaki hi chigatta
Even now, I do not waver
夢は今も　揺るがない
yume wa ima mo yuru ga nai
from that dream I dedicated myself to in my youth.
命が燃える
inochi ga moeru
My life burns bright.
Ｎｅｖｅｒ　Ｅｎｄｉｎｇ　Ｓｏｕｌ　情熱よ
Never Ending Soul jounetsu yo
Never Ending Soul of passion,
導け　天地を拓け
michibike tenchi wo hirake
guide me and open the path to heaven.
Ｎｅｖｅｒ　Ｅｎｄｉｎｇ　Ｗｏｒｌｄ　打ち立てよう
Never Ending World uchitateyou
Let's create a Never Ending World!
永遠の絆が誇り
eien no kizuna ga hokori
Boasting an eternal bond,
おまえと夢見た世界を　この手に　掴もう
omae to yumemita sekai wo kono te ni tsukamou
you and I will grasp the world we dreamed of.
～♪
Preview
We are the king and the sword that have been entrusted with the future of all of China!
（信）俺たちは
中華全土の未来を託された王と剣だ
Now a new light is born.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）今 生まれる新たな光
まだ見ぬ激動の時代に輝け！
Shining onto a yet-unseen turbulent age!
Succession
End
Next time,
次回 “継承”